What's wrong, Yuumi?
I have a feeling there's a lot
more at stake here than we think.
This will require some explaining.
While all VRMMOs originate
from the SEED program,
there's a difference between
them and Elvime Online.
You see,
a stripped-down version of the Cardinal
System runs the other active VR Miss,
but the one that operates
this game is a copy of
the full-spec version
that ran Sword Art Online.
Full-spec version?
The original Cardinal System had a feature
which could automatically generate quests.
It would log onto the net
and search for various
legends and folklore
from around the world.
Then it would take the stories it found,
adapt the data, and use it to
generate an infinite number of quests.
How about this quest, then?
Is it auto-generated by Cardinal 2?
After seeing how that NPC was acting
just now, I have a feeling it is.
If that is the case here,
then no matter what you do,
this quest will end the
same way the myth does.
Just now, I ran a quick
check on my archives.
According to my data,
in taking into account the
Norse mythology ALO is based on,
this quest must end in a final war event.
The Frost Giants from
Jotunheim and Niflheim
aren't the only ones
who want to attack Arun.
Below Niflheim is a fiery realm called
Muspelheim, where the Flame Giants live.
According to the myth, they will attack
the World Tree and burn it to the ground.
Ragnarok, the twilight of the gods!
Uh-uh.
I don't buy it.
I can't believe this game system
would destroy its own maps on purpose.
It's got to be a mistake!
I'm sorry, but there's
no mistake about it.
The Cardinal System has the authority
to destroy its maps if it wants.
I know this because the original Cardinal
System's last task was destroying Aincrad,
the floating castle of Sword Art Online.
No way.
There goes my blacksmith shop.
There go my chances of
ever meeting my soulmate.
Even if this Ragnarok thing
happens and it all deletes,
can't the server be rolled back the way
it was from one of the backups it's made?
The system has an auto-backup
feature, but those files won't help.
It only saves player data, not field
data, so you can't restore everything.
Oh, I got it!
I don't got it.
You can say that again.
Stop razzing me.
I was trying to call a GM to
see if he knew about this.
It ain't happening now.
It's after hours.
Support's closed.
That figures.
It's Sunday morning
just before New Year's.
Kazuto?
We're running out of time.
Yeah.
Let's hurry and get to
the last level. Right!
Thank you.
Damn it
This isn't looking good, the gold one's
tough, nothing we do is slowing him down.
Yeah, this sucks.
If we only had a mage who can
cast attack spells in our party.
That's hilarious coming from you.
It wouldn't help anyway
because the dude in the back
with the high resistance to
magic would just move up.
Could this get any tougher?
Shockwave attack coming
up in three, two, one!
Su-phila-heil-a-gul-austul!
Flatsubal-a-bani!
Kirito!
I've only got about two and a
half minutes before I'm out of MP!
Kirito!
Kazuto, more than two-thirds
of this medallion's gone dark.
If we die now, we won't have time
to start over from the save point.
Thanks! Good to know!
Hey, guys!
There's one thing we haven't tried yet!
If we use sword skills with magic, we
might do some damage to this gold bastard!
It'll leave you wide open, though.
It's do or die time!
So what do you say we focus
our attack and wipe him out?
Hell yeah!
Just say the word and his ass is grass.
Silica, time for your bubble spell. Right!
Ready, and hit it!
Tina, bubble breath attack!
Joe!
Kirito!
We locked up!
This is it!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
This is how it comes to me.
For this world, for this world,
for this world, for this world,
Ah, we killed your pal.
Too bad for you.
Okay, what the hell was
that move you just pulled?
You don't want to know.
Oh, come on.
That was totally a new skill.
Well, it's not really a skill.
It's skill connect.
Skill connect?
Remember the last update?
You know it brought a bunch
of sword skills to ALO, right?
Well, even though we got those,
we didn't get unique skills like
dual wielding or the divine blade.
Well, hang on a sec.
You were dual wielding just now.
Technically, that wasn't dual wielding.
Huh?
I was using one-handed sword skills with
each hand and alternating between them.
If I'm lucky, I can keep it going without
any lag maybe three or four times.
Hmm no it's nothing
yui just deja vu is all
you're not off the hook
either what the hell!
Did you do just now i
don't think you want to
know oh come on i've
never seen anything like
that before it's an
extra skill i picked up
dual wielding don't pop
a blood vessel all right.
We can't stand around chatting all day.
Leafa, how much time
we got left? Oh, right.
At the pace we're going, we should
have maybe another hour or so.
That's it?
Yui, do you know how big these last
couple of floors are going to be? Yes.
The third floor is about 70
% the size of the second.
And the fourth floor is pretty
much just the boss room.
I figure the last boss fight will
take us 30 minutes to finish.
That means we only got about 30 minutes
to get to his room. That settles it.
The clock's ticking and the
King of Giants is waiting.
So let's get the lead out
and kick his giant ass!
Daddy!
You heard her.
As soon as everyone's got their HP and
MP restored, we'll hit that third floor.
Right!
I don't want to go.
Who are you?
Come on, guys!
The last boss is waiting!
Please, help me.
Let me out of here.
It's a trap. It's a trap.
It's so a trap.
Well, maybe it is.
Maybe it isn't.
What do you think, Yui?
She's an NPC.
Her core programming is connected to the
language engine module, just like Oortz.
Although, there is one
difference between them.
This one has an HP gauge.
Yeah, that's a big red flag.
If she's got an HP gauge,
we might have to fight her.
A trap.
Totally a trap.
Obviously a trap.
It might be a trap, it might not.
I don't know.
Either way, we can't
afford to take the chance.
We can't waste any more time.
We gotta get to Thrimmer
ASAP. Oh, right. Yeah.
We got a job to do.
Do not leave me. Please.
I beg you.
I know it's a trap.
I'm not stupid.
But even if it is a trap, even if
I know it's a trap, I don't care!
I can't just turn my back on
someone if they need help!
But even if...
even if it means we fail the quest,
and even if Arun gets destroyed,
if I got a chance to do some
good for someone, I will!
Because that's what being
a samurai is all about!
Don't worry, princess, I'm coming!
I'm free.
Thank you, fairy swordsman.
No worries.
Let me help you up.
No.
I can manage it.
Whoa!
The way out's kind of far, Dollface.
You gonna be okay to make it on your own?
I could, but I'm afraid I cannot
leave the castle just yet.
For you see, I must first retrieve my
people's treasure, which King Thrimmer stole.
If you would, fairy swordsman, please
let me accompany you to Thrimmer's room.
This is beyond fishy,
don't you think? Uh-huh.
Hey, uh, Kirito?
Alright, I can't stand seeing you beg.
Since we only got a little
further to go before the end,
and seeing as how we don't
know for sure it's a trap...
Yes!
You hear that?
You're coming with us, gorgeous!
We'll help you beat that jerk, Thrimmer.
We're in the same boat now,
so let's get wet together!
Oh, thank you, fairy swordsman.
Delete Klein's last comment
from your memory, Yui. Huh?
Freya.
Huh, she must be a mage.
Her MP's really high.
With the way they got
this dungeon laid out,
the final boss room should
be down those stairs.
Remember, he's the last boss, so he's going
to be way stronger than the other ones.
When you hit him, hit fast and hit hard.
Until we can figure out
his attack patterns,
we'll be on the defensive so no one
moves on until I say one last thing!
If you see his gauge
drop to yellow or red,
his attack patterns are gonna
change big time so watch out!
This is it guys get in there
and give it all you got!
Let's go.
Seiya, Fila, Zekken,
Hagel, Hogg, Margo, Ilto!
Oath, Nazar, Fijo, Leged,
Jnada, Kalinda, Yochi!
She boosted our maximum HP!
I didn't know a spell could do that!
Cha-cha-ching.
I wonder how much Yul's here.
Coo-chee-coo-chee-coo.
Who let the flies in?
The buzzing of their
wings is so irritating.
I shall crush them all before
they annoy me any further.
Winged alfheim insects,
have you burrowed down here on
the whims of Urt, the trollop?
Wretches, how dare you enter here?
Did you think you could steal my treasure?
If you tell me where I can find that
woman, I shall give it all to you gladly.
Huh, you think a samurai
gives a damn about gold?
Well, you can stick that
treasure right up your ass.
Better yet, let me give you a hand.
Lady Freya, how good of you to
grace us with your presence today.
I see you have left your cage.
Shall I take it you have come to your
senses and agreed to become my wife?
She's supposed to marry you?
Yes, she is.
That is why she came to this castle.
Isn't that right, my dear?
However,
the night before our wedding banquet,
I caught her sniffing
around my treasure vault.
As punishment, I locked
her in a cage of ice.
Hey, Kazuto, I know this story.
I read it before.
Thrimmer and Freya, a stolen treasure,
and something else, too. But what?
I will not become your wife!
These warriors and I are here to
put an end to your reign of evil!
I will return my treasure immediately!
Yes, that's the spirit, my lovely.
I would expect nothing
less from the woman whose
beauty and valor are
known throughout the land.
And as they say, the more noble the
flower, the more satisfying it is to pluck.
After I've snuffed the
life from these insects,
I shall shower you with extra affection.
You bastard!
Over my dead body!
I, Lord Kline, won't let you
lay a finger on Lady Freya!
Listen to the angry
little fly buzzing away.
Now then, it is time I began
celebrating my conquest of Jotunheim.
I shall start by crushing
the life from you.
It's on.
Listen to you.
We guys don't attack those. She says.
I'm going to keep
my eyes on my face.
I'm always talking to each other.
TV in the middle.
The heroes are for the future.
I'm going to be busy.
Thank you
so
much for watching.
I don't know what to say.
The whole thing about movies
is long during the day.
I'll tell you nothing,
I'll tell you nothing.
I'll tell you nothing?
You need anything...
Galibur.